in this problem
we need to modify the code that we've
been given
so that the user's input will be added
to the numbers array
when the numbers array has five elements
we want to stop looping and collecting
input from the user
and print the numbers array to the
screen
you can see that we've initialized a
local variable numbers on line 1
referencing an empty array because it
was initialized in this outer scope
we will be able to access it within the
block
of our loop as well as again on line 7
to print the array
the first thing we do when our loop
begins to execute
is we output enter any number to the
user
the user's input is converted into an
integer
with the string method 2i and stored in
the local variable
input our first task here
is just to figure out how to put the
user's input
into our numbers array and to
demonstrate how we can do this i'm just
going to
comment out our loop code right now
[Music]
and call the array push method on
numbers
let's pass in the number 5 as an
argument
and on line 7 will print numbers
[Music]
right now our numbers array has only one
element
five
we can push more elements into the array
if we'd like
and print the array each time
[Music]
now you can see first we've added 5 then
we add
1 and five remains in the array
finally we add three when we call puts
on an array
it prints each element as a string on
its own line
[Music]
now that we can see how push works and
that it mutates the calling array
we can think about how we want to use it
within our loop
so what we want to push into our array
is
the value referenced by the input local
variable
[Music]
so for now let's pass input as our
argument
to the array push method and just break
out of our loop
after one iteration
the program prompts us to input a number
let's input five and you can see that
five was printed back to the screen
and that's because we were printing the
elements within the numbers array
so this looks okay but we actually want
to collect
five numbers to put into our numbers
array
we can do that by checking the size of
the numbers array
so we can add a condition here to the
reserve word break
and only break if the size of our
numbers array
is equal to five let's run our code
[Music]
again
and you can see it just keeps prompting
us for more numbers
let's enter our fifth number and now it
prints each element of the array out for
us
one two three four five so
our code is working as we would expect